A Guide to the Edward H. Peeples, Jr. Papers, n.d. 1910, 1943-1994
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
Edward H. Peeples, Jr. Papers n.d., 1910, 1943-1994
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M 68
9.2 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated to VCU Libraries by Dr. Peeples.
Biographical Information
Dr. Edward H. Peeples, Jr. is Emeritus Associate Professor of Preventive Medicine and Community Health at Virginia Commonwealth University where he taught for more than thirty years. Peeples made most of his academic contributions in the fields of medical behavioral science, public health, epidemiology and sociology. But much of his research and writing dealt with contemporary issues of social justice and he spent most of his adult life as a civil rights advocate involved in a variety of human rights reforms in Virginia and other places across the south.
Born in Richmond on 20 April 1935, Peeples received a B.S. in Health and Physical Education from Richmond Professional Institute (now VCU) in 1957. He began his civil rights activity in 1955 while a student at RPI. In late 1959, soon after being discharged from the US Navy, he became a volunteer with the American Friends Service Committee in Prince Edward County, Virginia which had closed its public schools rather than racially integrate them. In February 1960, he participated in the first of Richmond's lunch counter sit-ins. He later did extensive field work and interviewing in Prince Edward which led to his Masters thesis, A Perspective on the Prince Edward County Virginia School Issue, at the University of Pennsylvania in 1963. From this he produced several documents, some of which were later incorporated into reports and briefings for the United States Commission on Civil Rights; the U.S. Department of Justice; and the U.S. Office of Education in their efforts to find a resolution to the Prince Edward County school closing issue.
Peeples received a M.A. in Human Relations (Intergroup Relations) from the University of Pennsylvania in 1963; and a Ph.D. from the University of Kentucky in Sociology with a Concentration in Medical Behavioral Science in 1972. He began his teaching career at the Medical College of Virginia and the Richmond Professional Institute in 1963, prior to their merger in 1968 forming Virginia Commonwealth University. During his long academic career, Dr. Peeples taught, conducted research, consulted and published in the fields of medical behavioral science (behavioral factors governing clinical practice in the helping professions), behavioral epidemiology (behavioral causes, complications and consequences of disease, injury and disability), public health and community medicine, violence prevention, research methodology, intergroup relations (including race and ethnic relations and minority health), and sociology.
He was appointed by the Richmond City Council in the early 1980s to the Commission on Human Relations where he was elected both Vice-Chair and Chairman and also was appointed to the Richmond Environmental Commission in the early 1990s. Since his retirement in October 1995, Peeples has continued his efforts to help document the struggle for Civil Rights in Virginia and has worked with historians, researchers, numerous repositories, and with the Martin Luther King, Jr. Commission of the Virginia General Assembly. He is married and has four daughters and two grandchildren.
Higher Education:
Ph.D., University of Kentucky, 1972, Concentration in Medical Behavioral Science, major: Sociology, minor: Anthropology. Dissertation: Rank Differentiation and Somatic Disease: A Systematically Derived Inventory of Propositions
M.A., University of Pennsylvania, 1963, Human Relations (Intergroup Relations). Thesis: The Prince Edward County Virginia School Issue
B.S., Virginia Commonwealth University (formally Richmond Professional Institute), 1957, Health and Physical Education, Honor Graduate Award for Leadership, Outstanding Senior Athlete Award, 1956-57.
Academic Appointments at Virginia Commonwealth University:
1995-present Associate Professor Emeritus of Preventive Medicine and Community Health
1976-1995 Associate Professor of Preventive Medicine, Dept. of Preventive Medicine and Community Health (DPMCH) and Department of Biostatistics
1991-1992 Scholar-in-Residence, University Honors Program
1991-1995 Faculty Research Associate, Center for Public Service
1972-1976 Assistant Professor of Preventive Medicine, DPMCH
1968-1972 Assistant Professor of Sociology and Preventive Medicine, Departments of Sociology/Anthropology and DPMCH
1963-1965 Instructor in Sociology, School of Nursing, Medical College of Virginia
1963-1964 Instructor in Sociology, Richmond Professional Institute, part-time
Academic Appointments at Other Institutions:
1985-1986 Lecturer in Medical Sociology, University of Richmond, part-time
1967-1968 Instructor in Medical Sociology, Dept. of Behavioral Science, Colleges of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Kentucky, Lexington
Scope and Content
The collection consists of materials collected by Dr. Peeples in the field of hunger, poverty, and racial issues in the United States and abroad. There is considerable information on the fight for integration in Virginia in the 1960s. It includes his thesis on the Prince Edward County school issue in the late 1950s and early 1960s as well as many newspaper articles that document that period. A large portion of this collection is made up of numerous types of publications.
Arrangement
Alphabetical
Contents List
- Oversize newspaper articles, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  One box of oversize newspaper articles on city race relations and court ruling texts on desegregation.
- ACLU, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Anti-Defamation League, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Articles on Busing, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Central Virginia Organizations, 1965-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Citizens for Humane and Effective Corrections, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Clippings: Richmond and Richmonders, 1980-1984, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence - Agendas, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence - Membership, Contacts, Addresses, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence - Richmond Human Rights Coalition, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Housing Opportunities Made Equal, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Prison Visitation Project, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Race - Pamphlets, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Race: Richmond Civil Rights Individuals, 1940, 1960, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Race and Reason: A Yankee View, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Richmond Commission on Human Relations, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Richmond Council on Human Relations, 1964-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Richmond Human Rights Coalition, 1976-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Richmond Human Rights Coalition - Proposal, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Richmond Memorable Events, 1965, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Richmond Peace Education Center, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Richmond Politics, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Richmond Race, etc. (one of two), 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Richmond Race, etc. (two of two), 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Richmond Race and Intergroup Relations, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Richmond Schools - Race n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Southern Exposure, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- VCU, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Virginia Council on Human Relations, 1962-1965, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Newspaper articles on race relations in South Africa, n.d. (1960s-1980s) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- A Hundred Years Later, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- A Memorandum to Municipalities: A Guideline, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- A Southerner Looks at Negro Discrimination, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- A Tale of Time and Toilet Tissue, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- A Virginia View of Race and Reason - reprint from the New South, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- A Year in the Life...Bridgeton High School, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Albany - A Study in National Responsibility, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- American Friends Service Committee - The Trail of Broken Treaties, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- American Opinion - "One Dozen Candles", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Annotated Bibliography of Publications and Reports, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Appalachian South - A Bibliography, n.d., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Appalachian South - Appalachian South, The, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Appalachian South - Mountain Life and Work, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Appalachian South - Mountain Life and Work, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Assault upon Freedom of Association, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Big Lie, The - Who Really Told It?, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Children and Racial Demonstrations - reprint from American Scholar, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Citizen, The, 1964, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Civil Rights, The Legislative Record, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Communism - Misc. Booklets n.d., 1957 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Communism - Newsletter on Comparative Studies 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Communism - Newsletter on Comparative Studies, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Communism - Newsletter on Comparative Studies, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Congressional Record - re: Civil Rights, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Cracking the Color Line - Non-Violent Methods, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Crisis Without Violence, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Economic Salvation through Regressive Sacrifice, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Education - A Handbook For Educators, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Education - Bulwark of Segregation, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Education - Children: Black and White, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Education - Citizens for Public Education, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Education - Cooperative Extension Education, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Education - Equality Through Integration, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Education - How Classroom Desegregation Will Work, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Education - National Education Program, The, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Education - Next Steps in the South, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Education - Prince Edward School Foundation, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Education - Journal of Educational Sociology, 1954, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Education - If the Schools are Closed, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Education - Public Schools and the Economy of Virginia, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Education - Truth about Desegregation in Washington Schools, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Education - Amelia County Economic Data, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Education - Misc. Prince Edward School Case, n.d., 1961, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Education - Sanctuaries for Tradition: Virginia's New Private Schools, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Education - School Segregation Northern Style, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Education - Study - Prince Edward County: Segregation to Closed, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Education - Statistical Summary of School Segregation, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Education - Public School Segregation and Integration in the North, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Education - Progress Report, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Education - Southern College Education Project (SCEP), 1963 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Education - Education in America - Saturday Review, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Education - New South: Six Years of Southern Free Choice, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Education - Black Belt Schools, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Education - Southern Education Report, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Education - Charting Private Schools in Virginia, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Education - Look - The Lost Years: Prince Edward County, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Education - National Education Program, n.d., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Congressional Record - 87th Congress, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles (one of four), 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles (two of four), 1963 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles (three of four), 1963 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles (four of four), 1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Powhatan County Articles, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Prince Edward County Articles, 1963, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Tuition Grants Articles, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Amelia County Articles, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Brunswick County Articles, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - James City Articles, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - King and Queen County, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles (one of four), 1964 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles (two of four), 1964 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles (three of four), 1964 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Newspaper Articles (four of four), 1964 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Prince Edward County Articles (one of three), 1964 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Prince Edward County Articles (two of three), 1964 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Prince Edward County Articles (three of three), 1964 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Private School Articles, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Surry County Articles, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Articles (one of two), 1965 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Newspaper clippings, articles on integration - Misc. Articles (two of two), 1965 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Eugenics and Race, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Federal Dollar and Nondiscrimination, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Gentleman from Mississippi, The 1961 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Ghetto, The: A Bibliography, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Grape Strike, The, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Health Care and the Negro Population, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- H.R. 7152 - The Civil Rights Act of 1963, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- How Southern Conference Leaders Became Standing Goodwill Group, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Hunger in America - reprint from The New York Times, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Hunger in Chicago - reprint from The Chicago Sun Times 1969 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Hunger in our Midst, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Institute for Research on Poverty, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Insurgent, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Integrator, The, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Intimidation Reprisal and Violence, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Journal of Intergroup Relations, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Letter to a Member of a White Citizen's Council, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Liberty Letter, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Memorial - Martin Luther King, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Methods and Cost of Incorporation in Virginia, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Monroe, N.C.Turning Point in American History, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Mountain Families in Poverty, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Muslim Herald, The, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Negro and Employment Opportunities in the South, The, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Negro Digest, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Negro in the United States, The - A list of Significant Books, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- New Wind in the Old South - reprint from the Christian Science Monitor n.d. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Newsweek - The Negro in America, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Northern Face, The, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Pamphlets, Misc., n.d., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Population and the American Future, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Population Bulletin, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Poverty Programs and Social Mobility, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Public Opinions and Attitudes about Mental Health, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Progressive, The, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Race Heredity and Civilization - Human Progress and the Race Problem, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Race Traitor, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Report of the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorder, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Selected Materials on Race, Racism, and Intergroup Relations, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Slovenski Oktet, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 16)
- South Africa - Dr. H.F. Verwoerd on South Africa n.d. (Box 10, Folder 17)
- South Africa - In Defense of South Africa, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 18)
- South Africa - In Africa Today: The Truth that Hurts, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 19)
- South Africa - Indian South Africans, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 20)
- South Africa - International Liquidity and Gold, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 21)
- South Africa - Orange River Project, The, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 22)
- South Africa - South Africa - in fact, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 23)
- South Africa - Transkei Emancipation Without Chaos, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 24)
- South Africa - Good Out of Africa, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- South Africa - South African Indian, The, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- South Africa - South African Scope, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- South Africa - South Africa- A Western Society, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 28)
- South Africa - Digest of South African Affairs, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- South Africa - The Identity Struggle in South Africa, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- South Africa - South Africa offers Great Opportunities, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- South Africa - South African Tradition, The, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- South Africa - Your Bantu Servant and You, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 33)
- South Africa - South West Africa, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 34)
- South Africa - Misc. newspaper articles, 1962-1966 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- South Africa - Misc. newspaper articles, 1964-1966, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- South Africa - Misc. leaflets, pamphlets, etc., n.d., 1958, 1961, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- South Africa - Africa Institute, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- South Africa - South Africa and the World in Defense of South Africa, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- South Africa - Misc. correspondence, 1962, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- South Africa - South Africa: A Bright Spot on a Dark Continent, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- South Africa - New African, The, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- South Africa - Friends of Rhodesian Independence, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Survival and Independence - James McBride Dabbs, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Tent City "Home of the Brave", n.d. (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Toward Equality- Baltimore's Progress Report, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Transaction Society, 1970, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Virginia Poll Tax Slips, 1946-1970 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- A Freedom Budget for All Americans, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- A Landmark Decision On Segregation In Housing: Jones v. Mayer, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- A Manual for Direct Action, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- A Manual on Alcoholism, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Africa South, [one of two] 1957 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Africa South, [two of two] 1957 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Africa South, [one of two] 1958 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Africa South, [two of two] 1958 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Africa South, [one of two] 1959 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Africa South, [two of two] 1959 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Africa South in Exile, [one of two] 1960 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Africa South in Exile, [two of two] 1960 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Africa South in Exile, [one of four] 1961 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Africa South in Exile, [two of four] 1961 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Africa South in Exile, [three of four] 1961 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Africa South in Exile, [four of four] 1961 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Appalachian Bibliographical Subjects, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Biology of the Race Problem, The, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Catalyst, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Catalyst, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Catalyst, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Catalyst, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 22)
- Child Labor in Agriculture, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 23)
- Civil Rights in Kentucky Since 1863, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 24)
- Constitution of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 25)
- Continuing Crisis, The, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 26)
- Crime of Incitement to Group Hatred, The, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Democracy in Action, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Economic and Social Consequences of Racial Discriminatory Practices, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 29)
- Epitaph for Jim Crow, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Export and Industrial Profile of South Africa, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 31)
- Forms and Scope of Poverty in Kentucky, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 32)
- Framework for Love: A Study of Racial Realities, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 33)
- Freedomways, [one of two] 1961 (Box 12, Folder 34)
- Freedomways, [two of two] 1961 (Box 12, Folder 35)
- Freedomways, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 36)
- Freedomways, [one of two] 1965 (Box 12, Folder 37)
- Freedomways, [two of two] 1965 (Box 12, Folder 38)
- Health Consequences of Smoking, The, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- How Many People? A Symposium, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Hunger U.S.A., 1968 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Hunger - Why?, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- If We Had Ham, We Could Have Ham and Eggs,If We Had Eggs, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Journal of Intergroup Relations, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Journal of Intergroup Relations, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Journal of Intergroup Relations, Winter 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Journal of Intergroup Relations, Summer 1965 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Journal of Intergroup Relations, Autumn 1965 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Journal of Social Issues, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Madame X, 1910 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Man and the Economy, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Meet the G.D.R., 1966 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Negotiation of Desegregation in Ten Southern Cities, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Negro Families in Rural Wisconsin, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Negro People in America, The,, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Negro Voter in the South, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- New South, Summer 1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- New South, Fall 1967 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- New South, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Our Greatest Challenge: Human Relations, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- German Democratic Republic Outline, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Poverty and Deprivation in the U.S., 1962 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Price We Pay for Discrimination, The, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Proceedings of the Conference on the Child and Mental Health, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Proceedings of the Seventeenth Year of Nemours Foundation Conferences on Crippled Children, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Progress or Poverty, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Progress Report: Indians in Rural and Reservation Areas, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Progress Through Separate Development: South Africa in Peaceful Transition, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Race and Intelligence, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Race Problem, The: Segregation or Integration?, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Race: The New Challenge, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Recreation in Metropolitan Richmond, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 24)
- School Integration, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Segregation and Desegregation, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 26)
- Seven Psychological Principles versus Power Politics, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 27)